Guide to the Paul Berg Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Paul Berg papers
1953-1998
SC0358
Berg, Paul, 1926-
87.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Paul Berg, 1989, 1991, 2000, 2007, 2013.
Information about Access
Search files, student files, personnel files, letters of recommendation, and other confidential materials are restricted.
Biography
Biochemistry Professor at Stanford University since 1960, Berg received the Nobel Prize for chemistry in 1980 for "fundamental studies of the biochemistry of nucleic acids with particular regard to recombinant DNA." He was appointed Director of Stanford's Center for Molecular and Genetic Medicine in 1984. In 1967, Berg, working at the Salk Institute, redirected his study of protein synthesis from bacterial cells to tumor viruses. By 1970, this research had led Berg and his associates to conclude their experiments could form the basis of "man-made living matter." Spurred by growing ethical questions, Berg chaired the National Academy of Sciences 1975 conference which focused on the potential hazards of recombinant DNA research and resulted in the policy and quidelines which form the framework for genetic research.
Chronology
1952-1954: American Cancer Society fellow, Institute in Copenhagen and Washington University School of medicine. His work was concerned with clarifying how the master substances of heredity, DNA, transfers its genetic information to analogous molecules, known as RNA, which serve as templates for making proteins.
1954: Scholar in cancer research at University of Washington. His work on the genetic apparatus that directs the synthesis of protein earned Berg the Eli Lilly award in biochemistry in 1959.
1960: Stanford School of Medicine, associate professor of biochemistry and until 1967 continued work on protein synthesis. All this work was based on bacterial cells, but in 1967, he decided to do research on animal cells, taking a year's leave. He worked at the Salk Institute on tumor viruses.
1970: By about 1970, Berg and his associates began to think how they might use tumor viruses to bring new genes to animal cells - "man-made living matter" or "engineered a new genetic molecule." This raised the question of ethics, so, in 1973, they stopped experimentation.
1975: National Academy of Sciences sponsors meeting, chaired by Berg, whose purpose is to conduct a survey of potential hazards involved (Asilomar). This resulted in a set of recommendations to establish guidelines to put certain constraints on experiments; these were organized by the NIH and are used as guidelines today.
1980: Berg was awarded the Nobel Prize in chemistry for "fundamental studies of the biochemistry of nucleic acids with particular regard to recombinant DNA." Berg was also responsible for shaping "policy" for dealing with possible risks of recombinant DNA research.
1984: Appointed director of Stanford University's Center for Molecular and Genetic Medicine.
Scope and Content
Collection focuses on Berg's work with recombinant DNA and includes professional correspondence, 1959-1985; research lab notebooks for the years 1953-1986 which document his work with protein synthesis in bacterial cells and tumor viruses; records concerning the National Academy of Sciences conference on recombinant DNA research guidelines; records from his Stanford positions including administrative files, grant files, departmental records, student files, lectures, and symposia; reprints and illustrations; and videotapes and audiotapes.
Access Terms
National Academy of Sciences (U.S.).; Stanford University. Beckman Center for Molecular and Genetic Medicine.; Stanford University. Department of Biochemistry. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Molecular genetics.; Nobel Prizes.; Recombinant DNA--Research.; Science--Moral and ethical aspects.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1959-1985; Series 1
  - Correspondence A - J, 1959 - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence K - Z, 1959 - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence A - B, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence C - D, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence E - G, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence H - K, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence L - N, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence O - R, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence S, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence T - Z, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence on Positions, 1959 - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Comm. on Medical Education - Drafts and reports (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NAS - letters of congratulations, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Gordan Conference (Nucleic Acids), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - NIH Study Section - Physiological Chemistry, corresp., 1964 - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - NIH Study Section, correspondence, 1964 - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Comm. on Public Exercises & Public Events, 1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - University Public Health Committee corresp., 1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Comm. on Committees (Proposed Research) corresp., 1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - NAS - National Research Council, correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - NAS - Life Sciences panel, correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - NAS, correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, Publications Committee, correspondence, 1965 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Journal of Molecular Biology, correspondence, 1967 - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Orbit correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - NAS, correspondence, 1967 - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Post-doctoral applications, rejected, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence A - H, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence I - O, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence P - Z, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence A - H, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence I - O, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence P -Z, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Chron file, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Chron file, January - June 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Chron file, July -November 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence A - L, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence M - Z, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Chron file, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence A - K, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence M - Z, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Faculty/Technical Positions, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence post-doc rejects, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Chron file, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence A - N, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence N - Z, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Faculty positions, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence A - Z, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, post-doc rejects, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence NSF Human Cell Program, 1971 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence NSF Human Biology Steering Comm., 1970 - 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence "President's Biomedical Research Panel - Palade's Cluster", 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Jane Coffin Childs Fund, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, University Comm. on Research Policy, 1972 -1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Rich [Med. School Dean], 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Jane Coffin Childs, April 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Jane Coffin Childs meeting, 1974 Oct. 4 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Jane C. Childs Spring Meeting, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Council on Analysis and Projection (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Council on Analysis and Projection (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Scientific American (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - National Medal of Science, nomination A. Kornberg, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence A - C, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence D - G, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence H - L, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence M - Q, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence R - T, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence U - W, 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence A - C, 1978 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence D - F, 1978 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence G - I, 1978 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence J - N, 1978 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence R, 1978 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence S - Z, 1978 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Letters of Recommendation, A - D, 1973 - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Letters of Recommendation, E - H, 1973 - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Letters of Recommendation, J - O, 1976 - 1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Letters of Recommendation, R - Z, 1972 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Post-doc application rejects, Jan - June 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Post-doc application rejects, July - December 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Travel Correspondence - lectures/symposia, 1982 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1-79)
  - Travel Correspondence - lectures/symposia, 1980 - 1981 (Box 7)
- Research lab notebooks, 1953-1986; Series 2
  - Paul Berg
    - Methods (Salk Institute), 1967/68 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mut 51 - 78 (Salk Institute), 1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - RNA - Isolation from Tissue Cultures, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - PY (P.B.) (La Jolla), 1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Mut 79 - 141 (Salk Institute), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Mut 142 - 225 (Salk Institute), 1968/69 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - AA - Incorporation (Amino acids ?), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - EM (Electron Microscopy) of TSA viral DNA's, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nicking-Enzyme (F.C.), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Nicking-Enzyme II (F.C.), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Virus I V-1 to V-57 (M.D.), 1969/71 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - DNA-Synthesis in Nuclei (M. D.), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - c-RNA-Synthesis in vitro (Py), 1970/71 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Cot 1, 1970/71 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Hin Fragments (SV 40), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Cot 2, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Acetate III, 1954-55 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Acetate IV, Part 1, 1955-56 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Acetate IV, part 2, 1955-56 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Synthesis of amino acyl adenylates, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Synthesis and study of adenyl-amino acids, 1956 Sept. - 1957 May (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Amino acid incorporatio into RNA, I, 1957 May - 1958 July (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Amino acid incorporatio into RNA, II, 1958 July - 1959 April (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Purification of e. coli RNase, 1958-59 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Purification of RNA, 1959 Jan. - May (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Acetate incorporation, 1964 Mar. 18 - 1964 June 2 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Acetate incorporation, 1964 June 23- Sept. 22 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Purification of amino acid activating enzymes, 1958 June - October (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Methionyl Act-Enz (Yeast) I, 1955-56 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Unlabeled [Acetate II ?], 1954 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Acetate I, 1953-54 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - GLy-RNA Synthetase I, 1965 July 11 - 1966 Aug. 26 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - GLy-RNA Synthetase II, 1966 Aug. 25 -1967 Apr. 12 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - GLy-RNA Synthetase III, 1967 July 14 - Aug. 14 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Prep. & triphosphates (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Growth curves, 1966 Sept. 19 - 1967 July 6 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Preparation of ARPP+P+, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Vancouver, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Paris experiments, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Polyama Cot Data (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Science article, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - General thoughts on suppression (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Notes for paper on level of suppression (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Mechanism of missense suppression (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Dieckmann/Berg
    - COT II A, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - COTs for publication (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - SV Plaque Morphology Mutants, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Isolation of SV 40 Complex, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - SV 40 Mutants (Plaque Assays), 1974/1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - SV 40 Mu, Dn'ase (Mutants M. D.), 1975/1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - SV 40 Mu Late and Early (dl 861), 1975/1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - SV 40 Mu, Complementation (Mutant Characterization Complementation), 1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Replication Ori, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - SV 40 Mu, Hpall, Early and Late, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Lagerkrist, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Plasminogen Activator, 1977/1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Tag Function (Doefler), Dieckmann, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Restriction Mapping of Yeast t-RNA Inserts, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - beta Globin, 2kb in SV, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - alpha- and beta-Globin in SV, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Berg/Dieckmann/Hoshi
    - Mouse Embryos, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - NIH Guidelines, 1980, 1982, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - TC June Hoshi, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - [Untitled], 1974/75 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - [Untitled], 1976/77 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - [Untitled], 1978 to 1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - [Untitled], 1980/81 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - [Untitled], 1982 to 1986 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Plaque Assays, 1972 to 1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Notebooks by others
    - Peter Powell's paper and notes (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Jack Preiss: ACC - adding enzyme, Book 1, 1959-60 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Jack Preiss: ACC - adding enzyme, Book 2, 1959-60 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Jack Preiss: ACC - adding enzyme, Book 3, 1959-60 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Jack Preiss: ACC-RNA end group identification (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Jack Preiss: E. Coli Lysates, 1958 Sept. - 1959 May (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Fred Bergmann notebooks (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Recombinant DNA, 1973-1977; Series 3
  - History, 1973 - 1977
    - Correspondence, A - H (pre Asilomar), 1974 - 1975 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, I - R (pre Asilomar), 1974 - 1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, S - Z (pre Asilomar), 1974 - 1975 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Asilomar Administrative Materials (conference coordinator) (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Asilomar Meeting Material (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Final Report (originals) (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Asilomar statement documents (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - NAS Final Report (Working Papers) (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (post Asilomar), 1975 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (post Asilomar), 1976 - 1977 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (pre Asilomar) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1973 - 1977
    - News articles, prior to 1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - News articles, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - News articles, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - News articles, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Recombinant DNA Controversy at Ann Arbor, Michigan (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - NIH Director's Advisory Committee Meeting, Feb. 9 -10, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Kennedy Hearings Cambridge Controversy (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Non-NIH Guidelines (USA & abroad) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Index, RDR Reference lists, RDR Master of selected articles (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (MIT meeting), 1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Manuscripts, 1974 - 1977 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Recombinant DNA Research Vol. 1, US Dept HEW, NIH, August 1976: (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Draft: Environmental Impact Statement Guidelines for research involving Recombinant DNA Molecules, 1976 Aug. 19 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - NIH Recombinant DNA research minutes/meeting reports etc., 1976 - 1977 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Cambridge City Council Matters (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Published Reactions to NIH Guidelines on RD Research (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Reply to Chargaff letter (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - WHO on Recombinant DNA Molecules (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Germ warfare correspondence (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "Genetic Scientists: Facing the Mutant Microbe," Rolling Stone, June 19, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "Genetisk Manipulation," INGENIOREN, Sept. 22, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - DNA: meetings/hearings/publications (Box 22)
    - DNA: essays (Box 23)
    - Recombinant DNA articles/clippings, 1976 - 1977 (Box 25)
    - DNA: copies of Berg's Senate Testimony (Box 25)
- The Salk Institute, 1972 - 1976; Series 4
  - CV of Personnel for Dr. Paul Berg (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Salk Institute: Correspondence, Holley's Lab, Salk Personnel listing (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Banbury Center - Cold Spring Harbor Lab, (Initial attempts at Berg et al II - corresp -, Bio-hazards of Viruses), circa 1977 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Administrative files, 1968-1984; Series 5
  - Manuscript - Biofuture: Confronting the Genetic Era, pp. 1 - 465, by Burke K. Zimmerman, undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Grant files ca., 1974 - 1982 (Box 16)
  - Reprints (Box 16-17)
  - Faculty applications, post-doc applications (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1969 July 1 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Meetings - Agendas - Minutes, 1968 - 1969 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Senate - Agenda - Minutes, Jan - Dec 1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Meeting, 1971 - 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Meeting, 1972 - 1973 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Minutes and Memos, 1979 Sept. - 1980 Aug. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Minutes and Memos, 1979 Sept. - 1980 Aug. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Minutes and Memos, 1980 Sept. - 1982 Aug. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee, Dec 1971 - March 1973 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Executive Committee, April - Dec 1973 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Weekly-Minder, 1971 - 1972 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Weekly-Minder, 1972 - 1973 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Hearings/Committees on Recombinant DNA (US Senate/State legislatures), 1976 - 1977 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Grant files and Disk files (Box 20)
  - Post doc files, 1981-1984 (Box 20-21)
  - Trip Files: lectures/symposia, 1975 - 1980 (Box 21)
  - Trip files/lectures/symposia (Box 22)
  - National Academy of Sciences Council Meeting, 1980 Oct. 26 (Box 23)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Hearing, 1981 May 6 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript Reviews completed (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Potential post-doctoral fellows (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Seminar Invitations declined (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Misc. check requests (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Medical School Biohazards Committee (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Audiovisual Materials, Series 6
  - Illustrations for publications (Box 26-27)
  - Seminar, Part I and Part II, 1987 Nov. 11; 2 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 28)
  - "Genetic Engineering: Challenge and Responsibility,", 1975 Mar 7; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 28)
  - "Dissections and Reconstruction of the SV40 Genome," NIH Lecture, 1976 Nov 17; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 28)
  - William H. Stein, lecture at Rockefeller University, 1984 Mar 16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 28)
  - Untitled, 1 audio cassette (Box 28)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1991-020
  - News clippings on DNA research, 1975 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Business correspondence, 1975 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal correspondence, re: Asilomar, 1975 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Comments and revisions of Asilomar Report: drafts and letter, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - News clippings on Ethics and Guidelines for Genetic Research, 1975 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Essays on the ethics of science/DNA research: (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Benefits of Saying YES! by Paul Ehrlich, (1975)
    - Toward an International Ethic of Science by Sergent Shriver, (1975)
    - Untitled - final version of the bioethics story with letter to Berg from S. F. Moran, (1975)
    - Scientists with a Secret" by Spencer R. Weart, (1976)
  - Memos and info on conferences: Asilomar Conference - programs, roster, memo; Joint MRC/ARC/SRC Conference on Recombinant DNA, (1975) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - International Conference on Recombinant DNA Molecules: memos, contract and budget (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ASILOMAR Conference: "Summary Statement of the Asilomar Conference on Recombinant DNA Molecules" manuscript and "Report of the Organizing Committee of the Asilomar.. ." drafts (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - DNA Testimony to Senate Committee, incoming and outgoing correspondence, testimony by Berg for the Subcommittee on Science, Technology, and Space, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Recombinant DNA Correspondence, 1979 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Addresses/Conferees (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Recombinant DNA: correspondence and related matters, 1976 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notebook: misc. letters and reports on recombinant DNA and conferences, NIH Advisory Committee, Environmental Impact Statement (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, Current Guidelines for Research in Recombinant DNA molecules, Members of the Recombinant DNA Program Advisory Committee - memos, letters, drafts, minutes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2001-092
  - Office files (Box 1)
  - Office files (Box 2)
  - Binder (Box 2)
  - David Singer (Box 3)
  - AMBO/AMBL (Box 3)
  - Engelhardt Institute, July 1999 (Box 3)
  - Tokyo Univ. Bio Inauguration (Box 3)
  - Lasker Foundation (Box 3)
  - Glenn Foundation (Box 3)
  - SKB proposals (Box 3)
  - Genes & Genomes: Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Exploring: Early correspondence (Box 3)
  - Dealing with Genes: Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Beckman Center Newsletters (Box 3)
  - Fellowship support (Box 3)
  - Possible students (Box 3)
  - Job applicants (Box 3)
  - Research Students: Stanford policies (Box 3)
  - Others' lab students: recs, nominations (Box 3)
  - Postdocs: general (Box 3)
  - Postdoc/grad student status (Box 3)
  - Postdocs accepted (Box 3)
  - Postdocs rejected (Box 3)
  - Students accepted (Box 3)
  - NIH 13235:
    - 1996-7 NIH Renewal GM 13235 (Box 3)
    - 1995-6 NIH Renewal GM 13235 (Box 3)
    - 7/87-6/92 NIH Renewal GM 13235 (Box 3)
    - 1989-9 NIH ROI 13235-22 (Box 3)
  - Aging Grant:
    - 1995-6 Aging Grant renewal (Box 3)
    - 1994-5 Aging Grant renewal (Box 3)
    - 1993-4 Aging Grant renewal (Box 3)
    - 1992-3 Aging Grant renewal (Box 3)
    - 1990 Aging Grant (Box 3)
    - 1990 Aging Grant binder (Box 3)
  - NIH AIDS: Davis/Berg AIDS grant (Box 3)
  - CMB Grant (Box 3)
  - Dzau Cardiovascular Training Grant (Box 3)
  - Training Grant (Box 3)
  - Bergfest (Box 3)
  - IOM Patent Study Group (Box 4)
  - cDNA Patent Letter (Box 4)
  - Trip files, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
  - Trip files, 1990-1993 (Box 5)
  - Reprints 1951-79 (Box 5)
  - Reprints 1980-2000 (Box 6)
  - Course materials:
    - Path to Code (Box 7)
    - Biochem 202 (1990-1997) (Box 7)
    - Human Bio 1993 (Box 7)
    - Hurlbut class (Box 7)
    - DB229 Molec. & Genetic Medicine (Box 7)
    - Medicine 229 (Box 7)
    - Cell Sciences course (Box 7)
  - ASCB 1995 (Box 8)
  - ASCB 1997 (Box 8)
  - CASBS (Box 8)
  - Chulabhorn Research Institute (Box 8)
  - Rep. George Brown correspondence (Box 8)
  - Human Genome Program Advisory Cte. (Box 8)
  - Gerontological Society of American (Box 8)
  - CA Academic Standards Commission (Box 8)
  - PB Personal (Box 8)
  - SF United School District Advis. Council (Box 8)
  - NFBR 194-5 (Box 8)
  - NFBR 1996 (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - NFBR 1997 (Box 8)
  - Mabel Beckman (Box 8)
  - Beckman F GAC 1990-1997 (Box 8)
  - French Academy of Science (Box 8)
  - 5 binders Beckman design corrections (Box 8)
  - Beckman Fundraising 1980-1989:
    - Fundraising correspondence 1980-1989 (Box 9)
    - Crocker proposal (Box 9)
    - Genentech (Box 9)
    - Communications with Kennedy 1984 (Box 9)
    - Communications with Crowley 1984 (Box 9)
    - Communications with Purpura 1984 (Box 9)
    - Discussions with Dean 1986 (Box 9)